<document>
    <section>
        <title>Big crested mastiff bat</title>
        <text>The big crested mastiff bat (Promops centralis), is a bat species from South and Central America.</text>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Taxonomy</title>
        <text>It was described as a new species in 1915 by British zoologist Oldfield Thomas. The holotype had been
            collected by George F. Gaumer, and was presented to Thomas via Osbert Salvin.[2]
        </text>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Description</title>
        <text>It can be differentiated from the other species of Promops, the brown mastiff bat, by its longer forearm.
            The brown mastiff bat has a forearm length less than 50 mm (2.0 in), while the big crested mastiff bat has
            one greater than 51.5 mm (2.03 in). It has a dental formula of
            1.1.2.3
            2.1.2.3
            for a total of 30 teeth.[3]
        </text>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Biology and ecology</title>
        <text>It is a social animal, roosting in small colonies of up to 6 individuals during the day. These roosts
            consist of the space underneath tree bark, the undersides of palm leaves, or tree hollows.[3] It navigates
            and detects prey using echolocation. Its search calls have an average duration of 20.6 ms, with a starting
            frequency of 23.0 kHz, an ending frequency of 25.6 kHz, and a peak frequency of 24.7 kHz.[4]
        </text>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Range and habitat</title>
        <text>The big crested mastiff bat is found in Central and South America. It is found in the following countries:
            Argentina, Belize, Bolivia, Brazil, Colombia, Ecuador, El Salvador, French Guiana, Guatemala, Guyana,
            Honduras, Mexico, Nicaragua, Paraguay, Peru, Suriname, Trinidad and Tobago, and Venezuela. It is found at a
            range of elevations, from sea level to 1,800 m (5,900 ft) above sea level.[1]
        </text>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>References</title>
        <text>
            1. Solari, S. (2019). "Promops centralis". The IUCN Red List of Threatened Species. 2019:
            e.T88087651A22036112.
            2. Thomas, Oldfield (1915). "The Annals and magazine of natural history; zoology, botany, and geology".
            Annals and Magazine of Natural History. 16 (91): 61–64. doi:10.1080/00222931508693686.
            3. Gardner, A. L. (2008). Mammals of South America, Volume 1: Marsupials, Xenarthrans, Shrews, and Bats. 1.
            University of Chicago Press. p. 434-435. ISBN 978-0226282428.
            4. González-Terrazas, Tania P.; Víquez, Luis R.; Ibarra-Macías, Ana; Ruíz, Adrián Tonatiuh; Torres-Knoop,
            Leonora; Jung, Kirsten; Tschapka, Marco; Medellín, Rodrigo A. (2016). "New records and range extension of
            Promops centralis (Chiroptera: Molossidae)". Revista Mexicana de Biodiversidad. 87 (4): 1407–1411.
            doi:10.1016/j.rmb.2016.10.008.
        </text>
    </section>
</document>








