<document>
    <section>
        <title>Introduction</title>
        The <entity>Sappethoussent</entity> are a <entity>tribal species</entity> found on the
        <entity>planet Cottred</entity>.
        They are war-like and spend much of their lives in conflict with the
        <entity>various tribes of the Laterping species</entity>. They are also highly religious and have many
        <entity>customs and rituals</entity>
        dedicated
        to their <entity>pantheon of gods</entity>. <entity>Sappethoussent tribes</entity> follow a
        <entity>patriarchal society</entity>
        with a
        <entity>chieftain</entity>
        that rules with <entity>absolute authority</entity> which
        is derived from the <entity>mandate of Aphypopc</entity>, the
        <entity>patriarch of their pantheon of gods</entity>.
        In this work I will introduce <entity>aspects of Sappethoussent life</entity>, focusing on
        <entity>ritual bathing</entity>
        and their <entity>war with the Laterping tribes</entity>.
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Ritual Bathing</title>
        <entity>Each lunar cycle</entity>
        starts off with <entity>ritual bathing</entity>.
        <entity>A tribe of Sappethoussent</entity>
        will travel to <entity>a hot spring within their territory</entity>.
        <entity>The tribe shamans and males of the tribe</entity>
        will form a column seven men wide and begin to
        dance around <entity>the hot spring</entity> to ward away <entity>evil spirits</entity>. All the while,
        <entity>the females of the tribe</entity>
        will kneel down around <entity>the hot spring</entity> in
        a <entity>circle seven men deep</entity> and pray to <entity>Infloal</entity>, <entity>the matriarch of their
        pantheon of gods</entity>. <entity>The chieftain</entity> will then enter the <entity>hot spring</entity> and be
        blessed by the <entity>head shaman</entity> in the name of <entity>Iverated</entity>, the
        <entity>god of war and patriarch of the Sappethoussent pantheon</entity>. Following
        <entity>the chieftain</entity>,
        the <entity>men</entity> will the enter the <entity>hot springs</entity> for seven minutes,
        followed by <entity>the women</entity> who also bathe for seven minutes.
        At the <entity>conclusion of the ritual bathing</entity>, the
        <entity>men</entity>
        will prepare a <entity>pyre of Sanday wood</entity> and the <entity>head shaman</entity> will place seven
        <entity>white comberateepes</entity>
        onto the <entity>pyre</entity>. The <entity>chieftain</entity> will then
        light the <entity>pyre</entity> marking the <entity>start of the next lunar cycle</entity>.
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>War with the Laterping Tribes</title>
        The <entity>ritual bathing</entity> and <entity>start of the lunar cycle</entity> marks the
        <entity>beginning of raids on Laterping villages
        </entity>
        by the <entity>Sappethoussent</entity>. The
        <entity>main duty of the chieftain</entity>
        is to bring <entity>wealth and prosperity</entity> to their <entity>tribe</entity>. As most
        <entity>chieftains</entity>
        are patrons of <entity>Iverated</entity>, <entity>chieftains</entity> typically aim to
        bring <entity>wealth</entity> to their <entity>tribes</entity> by raiding nearby
        <entity>Laterping tribes</entity>.
    </section>

</document>
