<document>
    <section>
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <text>
            The Sappethoussent are a tribal species found on the planet Cottred. They are war-like and spend much of
            their lives in conflict with the various tribes of the Laterping species. They are also highly religious and
            have many customs and rituals dedicated to their pantheon of gods. Sappethoussent tribes follow a
            patriarchal society with a chieftain that rules with absolute authority which is derived from the mandate of
            Aphypopc, the patriarch of their pantheon of gods. In this work I will introduce aspects of Sappethoussent
            life, focusing on ritual bathing and their war with the Laterping tribes.
        </text>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Ritual Bathing</title>
        <text>
            Each lunar cycle starts off with ritual bathing. A tribe of Sappethoussent will travel to a hot spring
            within their territory. The tribe shamans and males of the tribe will form a column seven men wide and begin
            to dance around the hot spring to ward away evil spirits. All the while, the females of the tribe will kneel
            down around the hot spring in a circle seven men deep and pray to Infloal, the matriarch of their pantheon
            of gods. The chieftain will then enter the hot spring and be blessed by the head shaman in the name of
            Iverated, the god of war and patriarch of the Sappethoussent pantheon. Following the chieftain, the men will
            the enter the hot springs for seven minutes, followed by the women who also bathe for seven minutes. At the
            conclusion of the ritual bathing, the men will prepare a pyre of Sanday wood and the head shaman will place
            seven white comberateepes onto the pyre. The chieftain will then light the pyre marking the start of the
            next lunar cycle.
        </text>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>War with the Laterping Tribes</title>
        <text>
            The ritual bathing and start of the lunar cycle marks the beginning of raids on Laterping villages by the
            Sappethoussent. The main duty of the chieftain is to bring wealth and prosperity to their tribe. As most
            chieftains are patrons of Iverated, chieftains typically aim to bring wealth to their tribes by raiding
            nearby Laterping tribes.
        </text>
    </section>

</document>
